Hello.
So in this module I will be presenting the definition of a proximity integrated circuit card, which
is the Pic and the definition of a proximity coupling device, which is the PCD and how the communication
between them works.
So first of all, let's talk about the pic.
So what's a pic?
So a pic is a pocket sized card that has embedded integrated circuits.
A contactless smart card is a smart card that uses inductive coupling to to communicate with the reader.
Inductive coupling is the technology behind NFC, near field communication, and short range RFID radio
frequency identification in the 1350 six megahertz radio band.
Proximity.
Contactless smart cards are defined by the ISO 14,443 set of international standards.
The ISO 14,443 is divided into four layers.
The upper layers, ISO 15,443 four, specifies the contactless transport protocol.
We will talk about this later.
Sometimes referred to T to to t equal CL.
The application layer that comes on top of the contactless protocol is supposed to be the very same
ISO 7816 four that comes on top of the t equals zero or t equal one transport protocol.
So when I talk about the ISO 14,443 and I say that it's divided into four layers, I first, I mean
there is a first one, ISO 14,443 one that will present the whole physical aspects of the car.
So like the type of glasses, the EMF test, we will get back to this later.
We will detail all of all of these instructions.
Then the ISO 14,440 3-2 presents the different characteristics about the contactless card.
Like the field that that should support the bit rate or the speed that should also support, etc. etc.
then we have the ISO 14,440 3-3 that present the the layer three of communication.
I mean the digital communication, the first comments and answers between the reader and the card.
And then, as I said, the ISO 14,440 3--4 that specifies.
The the transport protocol, the contactless transport protocol and also the exchange of information,
etc., etc..
So we'll talk about these four layers later in the during the the presentation.
So what's a PCD?
So PCD is a proximity coupling device, which is a card reader for proximity integrated circuit cards,
which are the Pic.
So it's an RFID reader in fact.
So it's playing the role of a reader.
It gives access to the smart card instructions, it generates a field to activate the Pic.
And it can be developed for different applications like identity card readers or passport readers or
banking readers, or by phones.
So by the way, let's get back to the first slide.
So here the pic.
It can be different.
It can be in different applications.
For example tags for animals car keys uh passports, uh tags for the for the bags in the airport.
Transport cards and also tags for medicines.
However, for the reader it can be a banking reader but a reader for passport, etc., etc..
So the most important thing here is the communication between the Pic and the PCD.
How this communication works.
So as we said, a contactless smart card is a smart card that uses inductive coupling.
I'm always repeating this part because inductive coupling is the key of the communication between a
PCD and a pic, between a reader and a card.
In some cases we can call can call the reader a polar and the card a listener.
So, as I said, a contactless smart card is a smart card that uses inductive coupling to communicate
with its coupling.
Inductive coupling is the principle behind electrical transformers.
A primary coil is powered by an AC voltage and create a magnetic field.
The magnetic field induces a current in the secondary coil in the contact.
The case of contactless cards.
The primary coil is driven by a sinusoidal voltage at 1356, as you can see here in the picture, and
hence create a magnetic field, which is this one with a 1356 carrier.
1350 six megahertz carrier frequency.
This magnetic field is not constrained in a confined volume, as it would be the case in an actual transformer.
Instead, the field flows virtually freely within a part of the open air, limited only by the directivity
of the coil and the decrease of the magnetic waves.
This coil and its driven circuit forming the primary of a virtual transformer, is named the proximity
coupling device PCD.
When a mobile or a secondary coil is moved into the part of the space where the PCD is filled floats.
It comes to the in proximity to the primary circuit.
The transformer, once virtual, now becomes real.
The flow of the magnetic field through the secondary coil provides electrical power to a secondary passive
circuit.
As you may have guessed, this mobile part of the transformer made of a coil and of an electronic circuit
or a chip, for example, is a proximity integrated circuit card pick.
So here what you can see here in this picture.
So here the PCD is looks like a transformer.
The same thing for the second part which is the pack.
And here the magnetic field as you can see here is the one is the one generated by the field which will
create the current.
And the second part of this picture.
So the magnetic field emitted by the coupler not only provides a power supply to the card, but is also
suitable to convey data in both directions.
The coupler modulates its carrier to transmit information to the card, and the card uses load modulation
to answer.
We will get back to this later.
We will detail this part.
So the communication between the PAC and the PCD is based on the load modulation principle, which means
that the card is able to vary its impedance according to Ohm's law.
Under a fixed voltage, any variation of the impedance causes a variation in the current, and as this
is the case for any transformer, the variation of the current is in the secondary circuit is also noticeable
from the primary circuit.
This is how the PCD sees the PAC sensor.
In fact, the communication between the PKD Reader unit and the PHC card is described in the ISO 14,443
standard.
The downlink from the PKD unit and the PK card uses amplitude shift keying.
Ask.
Ask for amplitude shift keying.
For type A and load modulation in the uplink.
The type B uses non-return to zero instead of Manchester coding.
I will detail what I have just said about the communication in the next session, which presents the
different analog aspects of the analog communication between a PCD and a pack.